

CONTACT



judahavery.com



linkedin.com/in/judahavery



judahbavery@gmail.com



(802)-777-0970

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Unreal Engine 4/5
- Unreal Blueprint
- Unity
- C++ / C#
- Visual Studio
- Maya / Blender
- Confluence
- Jira
- **Perforce**
- **Adobe Suite**

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Technical Design
- Systems Design
- Combat Design
- Level Scripting
- Prototyping
- **Design Documentation**
- Strong Design Sense
- **Working Under Deadlines**

INTERESTS

- Surfing
- Snowboarding & Skiing
- **Running & Hiking**
- Tabletop Games

SUMMARY

Passionate designer experienced with building AAA quality systems in both technical and combat design roles. Design driven workflow coupled with experience collaborating alongside programmers, artists, and animators. Very eager and adaptable team member that's always happy to help.

EXPERIENCE

Unannounced Project - Respawn Entertainment

Combat Designer | December 2023 - Present

- Responsible for bringing multiple enemy AI from concept to ship, pitching the initial design, prototyping that design, and iterating through team feedback and playtesting
- Direct collaboration across departments, especially animation, tweaking enemy attack timing, tells, anticipation, navigation, personality, etc.
- Ownership of multiple AI combat systems, working extensively with Unreal blueprint, behavior trees, animation montages, and animation blueprints

Star Wars: Jedi Survivor - Respawn Entertainment

Technical Designer | Shipped Title | August 2022 - December 2023

- Unreal blueprint expert and point of contact for help with all things blueprint
- Responsible for multiple game systems like collectibles, AI burrowing behaviors, UI/UX features, level design features, and more
- Direct collaboration with Level Design, Encounters, Animation, Destruction, UI/UX, QA, Code, and departmental leads/directors
- At the finaling stage, helped to hunt down, reproduce, and solve bugs to bring the game to ship

Technical Design Intern | May 2022 - August 2022

- Interned while pursuing a bachelors in Game Design, where I was offered an immediate full time role, which I accepted in place of finishing my degree
- Acted with similar responsibilities to the above role, though smaller in scale

OTHER PROJECTS

Champlain College - The Game Studio | August 2019 - May 2022

- Collaborated with other multidiscplinary students to mimic industry workflows through small teams
- Often led the design of these projects and assisted the production, helping to steer the creative direction and keep the team on track for milestone goals
- Responsible for design documentation, systems design/programming, UI design/programming, and animation implementation

SNIPERPUNK | UI Designer & Web Developer | February 2021 - May 2022

- Passion project built by a group of students from Champlain College, still currently under development with the help of an independent publisher
- Fast-paced, top-down hero shooter with online multiplayer and pinball inspired combat

EDUCATION

High School Diploma | Computer Animation & Web Design

Center For Technology, Essex, Vermont | 2017 - 2019

- Started pursuing game design/development through a tech program in my final two years of high school
- Competed in nation-wide game development competitions both years after qualifying through placing 1st in the state